ANIK BISWAS

Seeking a challenging position as a Data Scientist, eager to contribute to team success through hard work. Passionate about building models that fix problems. Relevant skills include machine learning, problem solving, programming, and creative thinking. Clear understanding of Big Data, Data Analysis and training in Data Science. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in IT Industry. A B.TECH(CSE) with 2.9 years+ (33 months) of total experience.

CONTACT

anikbiswas94@gmail.com

+91 9038256684

Kolkata, WB, 712258

Github/anik-biswas

in linkedin/anik-biswas

SKILLS

Programming and Query language

Python SQL(Hive)



Software & Tools

Machine Learning (e.g. numpy, scipy, pandas, matplotlib...)

Data Modeling and EDA Deep Learning

(e.g. CNN, RNN, LSTM, GRU, NLP, CV)

Spark(PySpark) Hadoop **Tools**



(e.g. Athena, Bitbucket, Ambari, Jira, Git, Superputty, Sharepoint, Excel)

Miscellaneous Skills

Ability to analyze **Critical Thinking** Verbal communication skills

TRAININGS AND CERTIFICATES

Hackerrank certified Python Programmer

(ID: a3f021a4e01e) **Udemy certified in Spark**

: UC-1de0b320-5b20-4be3-b0d1-

bcc2e612987c)

Udemy certified in Big Data

(UC-e04d0376-ae72-4f4e-9fe9-

e73c97e70471)

Guvi(Guvi.in) certified in Deep Learning (Credential ID: 2q8e9Q965b6K1O6X1P)

WORK EXPERIENCE

₩ 05/2021 - Till Now

▼ Tekion India Pvt. Ltd, Bangalore

Data Analyst

- Automotive Retail Cloud, DMS(Data Management System) Services Team
- Description: Analyzed the data to pre-process, validate and transform to migrate dealer data to Tekion Platform, and Automate few modules of validation using Python, following the Agile methodology.
- Technologies used: SQL, Python, Hadoop.
- Tools used: Athena, Git, BitBucket, Jira, TAP

10/2020 - 04/2021

♀ Infosys Technologies Ltd, Pune

Data Analyst

- Banking domain, CRP(Credit Risk Platform) Team
- Description: Analyzed the data to calculate the credit risk for wholesale and cash. Processed data from different sources in a total of 3 layers, using Spark.
- Technologies used: Spark, Python, Hadoop.
- Tools used: Autosys, Git, Superputty, BitBucket, Jira

10/2020 10/2020

♀ Infosys Technologies Ltd, Pune

Big Data Developer and Data Analyst

• Description: "The data Ingestion"- As a part of enhancement I had created all the models for 35 new JDE tables across all 4 layers for the DMZ server.

Those large data sets would be coming from JDE (Data source) to Datalake via BODS SQL server, in Datalake we had to process the data via intermediate layer using Hive and sqoop(for exporting from Datalake to DMZ server) and had to create a new workflow for that.

- Troubleshooting and debugging the code(Finding RCA and to resolve) written in Hive/Spark/Sqoop.
- Monitor availability, performance of the jobs.
- Technologies Used: Hadoop, Hive(HQL query), Sqoop, Ambari, Ranger, Winscp, Azkaban.

6 08/2018 - 01/2019

♀ Infosys Technologies Ltd, Pune

System Engineer Trainee

- Description: 4.5 months of Industrial Training in Mysore Campus
- Technologies: Python, SQL, PHP, HTML, CSS, JS

EDUCATION

6 08/2014 - 07/2018

▼ Techno India University - Kolkata Computer Science and Engineering CGPA: 8.46

B.Tech(CSE)

6 05/2011 - 04/2013

• Uttarpara Govt. High School

Higher Secondary(12th Standard)

Stream: Science(Maths, Statistics, Physics, Chemistry)

Percentage: 70.8

1 05/2009 - 04/2011

Q Uttarpara Govt. High School

Madhyamik(10th Standard)

Board: W.B.B.S.E Percentage: 87.5

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Languages

Bengali English Hindi



Interests

Artificial Intellegence Renewable Energy Astrophysics Finance

Date of Birth: 02/08/1994Nationality: INDIAN

• Gender : Male

• Marital Status: Unmarried

 Present Address: 5/A/1, SHIBNARAYAN ROAD, UTTARPARA.

• Dist. - HOOGHLY, State - W.B., India

• PIN-712258.

PERSONAL PROJECTS AND ACTIVITIES

- Object Detection and Image Classification using CNN
- Music Recommendation System using Deep Learning
- Weather Prediction Model using ML
- Amazon Food Review using NLP
- Netflix Movie Recommendation System using EDA and ML
- **Self-Driving Car** using deep learning: I have created a project using available dataset using deep learning where the wheel angle is determined by itself.
- IMDB sentiment analysis: Created a mini project using Machine learning and deep learning to analysis and determine human sentiment(Positive/negative comments etc.) from their comments.
- **Fit Tracker**: Created a project from a dataset (from mobile sensor data like accelaretometer, gyroscope etc.) to track the human activity like walking, sitting etc.
- Works various small projects on ML, Random Forest, Classification, Regression, Deep learning, Computer Vision
- College Project Jarvis: (link: https://github.com/Jarvis) Artificial Intelligence Voice Assistant, Open Source Project Programmed on Python. Demo: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RICAxHefw6c.
- College B.Tech Project: Biometric Identification Using Fingerprint: Identification of every individual based on Fingerprint.

ACHIEVEMENTS, HONOURS AND AWARDS

- In Infosys: Got client appreciation several times for critical code fix on time.
- Our project was selected the best project in college several times.
- School: Won several prizes in Math and Science competition, the Devi Sethi Scholarship in 8th Standard.
 - Organized a Quiz and Debate competition in School..